

ÁLVARO ENRIQUE RUANO

alvaro.ruano90@outlook.com https://alvaroruano.me

PROFILE

Software Engineer helping businesses to accomplish their goals through the use of technology.

have ten years experience working on software development projects in the roles of: Software developer, Business Analyst, Project Manager and Software Engineering Manager.

SKILLS

- Team management (up to 14 people)
- FrontEnd development: AngularJS, ASP.Net MVC & WebForms, Django
- BackEnd development: WebAPI, WCF, MS SQL, MySQL, Sybase ASE, MongoDB
- DevOps: Git, TFS VS, Docker, CircleCI, TravisCI, CodeCov
- AWS Cloud: EC2, RDS, S3, Lambda, Cloud
 Formation

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER • CONDUENT • FEB 2017 - PRESENT

In charge of the development and quality assurance teams that provide support to a proprietary "Workers Compensation Bill Review system", including but not limited to:

- Data ingestion applications (XML, ANSI X12, PDF and TIFF images)
- Web Applications (SaaS offering)
- Data export applications, to partners and government entities
- Compliance systems

In addition to that, also responsible of the implementation of SLDC best practices, coding standards and the current migration to Microsoft Azure.

BUSINESS ANALYST • CONDUENT • APR 2015 - FEB 2017

In charge of the correct operation of the platforms used to report compliance information to the distinct state governments in the USA, this is achieved through the administration of technological and human resources, as well as the interpretation of the business requirements.

SR. DEVELOPER • AGROMERCANTIL BANK • APR 2015 - FEB 2017

In charge of the software development projects through all the phases of the SDLC, from requirements analysis to the deployment. Also provide production support for the systems created. Subsequently, in a role of team leader, take control of a portion of the project portfolio.

JR. DEVELOPER • CITIBANK • APR 2015 - FEB 2017

Design and develop new features for the e-Banking systems used in Central America. Execute the tasks established in the Software Development Lifecycle, completing the required deliverables.

EDUCATION

MBA • ENAE BUSINESS SCHOOL • 2020 (EXPECTED)

MASTER OF FINANCE • RAFAEL LANDÍVAR UNIVERSITY • 2016

• Academic Excellence Diploma

INFORMATION SYSTEMS ENGINEERING • RAFAEL LANDÍVAR UNIVERSITY • 2013

- Magna Cum Laude
- Excellence in Values Award 2012 Engineering Students Association (AEI)
- Basic Sciences Olympics 2009 (third place in Math) San Carlos University